

# LEONARDO J. MACEDO

Software Engineer | SysAdmin | BSS (Telco) Consultant



## **ABOUT ME**

About **9 years work experience** in support, operations and IT consulting for OSS/BSS Telco systems.

In the recent years, being part of production team as subject-matter expert of rating chain process, part of Ericsson Billing Convergent Solution (BSCS-IX) in technical issues, business support, deployments, and automation developer (scripting).

Critical spirit and problem-solving skills, having participated actively of risk and crisis management processes, proposing definitive and/or alternative technical solutions, always focused on service availability and service delivery as well as service level agreements attendance. Currently, working in software engineer master's thesis about benefits of Machine Learning to improve ITSM incident tickets classification process.

## **EDUCATION**

M.Sc in Software Engineering (In progress) | 2017 - 2019

Faculty of Engineering, University of Porto (FEUP) - Porto, Portugal

B.Sc in Computer Science | 2007 -

São Judas Tadeu Faculty - São Paulo, Brazil

# CONTACT

in macedojleo

macedojleo@gmail.com

macedojleo

🥱 macedojleo.github.io

S leonado.macedo

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### SEP, 2017 - PRESENT

#### Master degree student

Faculty of Enginering, Universisty of Porto

Presently I spend most of my time working on master's thesis "Automate ITSM Incident Management Process" with Machine Learning and Natural Language Processing (NLTK for Python).

SEP, 2009 - AUG, 2014

#### IT BSS Consultant

Conference - Porto

http://talkabit.org/

Orga Systems

BSS (Business support system) operation/production accountable for automating processes (scripting), customer requests, Incident ticket management, problems (troubletickets), and RFC technical validation role (risk analysis and mitigation, implementation, and validation)

AUG, 2014 - JUN, 2017

#### **IT Specialist**

Nextel Telecomunicações

BSCS iX convergent rating engine operation SME, ensuring performance and quality of the technical platform servers and applications besides vendor's, Dev Team, and QA Cooperation in order to guarantee the system availability according to the SLA

FEB, 2008 - SEP, 2009

## **Production Analyst**

Ericsson

Ticket Incidents and defects management providing in a timely manner a definitive, or at least, a contour solution (WA) in order to guarantee system reliability and stability keeping the system uptime according to SLA and KPI metrics.

#### FREE COURSES

2019	2018	2015
Mastering Ansible (in progress) UDEMY	Python for Engineering NTITEC (FEUP)	Oracle Database 11G Adm Ka Solution
2014	2006	2006
ITIL V3 - Foundations Ka Solution	Cisco CCNA V3 Senac - SP	Linux System Administrator Senac - SP

# OPEN SOURCE AND ACADEMIC PROJECTS

Ansible CI Tutorial	Automate IT Incident Management Process	
github.com/macedojleo/DOCKER_ANSIBLE	macedojleo.github.io/Aprendizagem-Computacional-em-ITSM/	
BDH - Monitorize Unix and Linux FS consuption	CosnFlix - Video Streaming Service	
https://macedojleo.github.io/BDH/	https://github.com/macedojleo/COSNFLIX	
7th Talk-A-Bit Tech	Pomar - Organic	

Food APP

https://gitlab.com/gigantedocil/pomar-mobileapp

## **SKILLS**

Development	IT Infrastructure	Languages
Shell Script & AWK	Linux &Unix	English
Python	Docker & Docker Compose	Spanish
Git & GitHub	Oracle SQL	Portuguese
Text Markup Languages	BMC Control-M	